Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- FILES CREATED AS EDITOR AND CONTRIBUTOR, 1914-1934 (Boxes 24-37)
  - Russkaia Mysl', 1914-1926
    - Marchenko, M. K., "Iz devnika voenogo agenta, 1905-1910," holograph (Box-folder 26: 12)
    - Meisner, Evgenii, "Vazhneishaia nravstvennaia zadacha russkikh emigrantov," typescript (Box-folder 26: 13)
    - Mintslov, S. R., "Za mertvymi dushami," typescript (Box-folder 26: 14)
    - Odinets, D. M., "Prisoedinenie Ukrainy k moskovskomu gosudarstvu," typescript (Box-folder 26: 15)
    - Olsuf'ev, D. A., "Bezhenskoe samoupravlenie-pis'mo iz Iugoslavii," typescript, 1922 (Box-folder 26: 16)
    - Pervukhin, M., "Fashizm - pis'mo iz Italii," typescript (Box-folder 26: 17)
    - Pogodina, V., "Obitel' skor'bi," holograph (Box-folder 26: 18)
    - Popov, A., "Lozungi i metody," typescript (Box-folder 26: 19)
    - Rklitskii, N., "Detskii pokhod - iz epokhi Dobrovol' - cheskoi Armii," holograph, 1922 (Box-folder 26: 20)
    - Rozenshil'd Paulin, "Opravdanie natsionalizma,", 1922 (Box-folder 26: 21)
    - Saksen-Al'tenburgskaia, E., letter to the editor, 1923 December 23 (Box-folder 26: 22)
    - Saldykov, V. N., "Poslednie dni Odessy v g. - vospominaniia krasnokrestnogo rabotnika," holograph, 1920 (Box-folder 26: 23)
    - Shishko, S. E.
      - "Ob otnoshenii teorii veroiatnostei k massovomu determinizmu i o gipoteze guy," holograph (Box-folder 26: 24)
      - Open letter to P. B. Struve (Box-folder 26: 25)
    - Schneider, D., "Vosstanie Kirgizov v tsentral'noi Azii v i likvidatsiia miatezha," typescript, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 26: 26)
    - Spektorskii, E. V., "Dostoevskii kak publitsist," typescript (Box-folder 26: 27)
    - Suleshov (Solov'ev), A., "Dva palomnichestva: 1. pokhvala Pochaevskaia. 2. Monastyr' Kniazia Lazaria," holograph, 1921 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - Tikhvinskii, M., "Uchreditel'noe Sobranie i rossiiskoe pravitel'stvo v Omske," holograph (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Timashev, N. S.
      - "Federativnoe nachalo i gosudarstvennoe ustroistvo Sovetskoi Rossii," typescript (Box-folder 27: 3)
      - "Pravovoe polozhenie lichnosti v Sovetskoi Rossii," holograph (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - Urusov, L. A., "Razreshemie zemel'nogo voprosa," holograph, 1923 (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - Voronetskaia, M., untitled writings (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Vozrozhdenie (Paris), 1917-1928
    - General
      - Correspondence of Vozrozhdenie, with Petr Struve, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 27: 7)
      - Material related to the founding of Vozrozhdenie
        - Official papers, 1925 (Box-folder 27: 8)
        - Correspondence with potential contributors, 1925 (Box-folder 27: 9)
      - Reactions to Vozrozhdenie in émigré press (Box-folder 27: 10)
      - Struve, Gleb, "Stranitsa iz istorii russkoi zarubezhnoi pechati. Nachalo gazety Vozrozhdenie," typescript, undated (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - Material related to Petr Struve's departure as Editor-in-Chief, 1926-1927
      - Correspondence, 1927
        Reactions to Struve's departure.
        - Individuals (Box-folder 27: 12)
        - Organizations and other publications (Box-folder 27: 13)
      - Struve, Petr, "Pochemu i kak menia vytesnili iz Vozrozhdeniia," holograph draft and typescript copy, undated (Box-folder 27: 14)
      - Zaitsev, K., "'Rossiia Petra Struve ili ogukashevannoe 'Vozrozhdenie'?," holograph draft, undated (Box-folder 27: 15)
      - Miscellaneous material compiled by Gleb Struve, typescript, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 27: 16)
      - Struve, Gleb, "K istorii gazety Vozrozhdenie. Konflikty v mae-noiabre g. i v mae-avguste 1927 g. i sviazannyi s nimi krizis v Rossiiskom Tsentral'nom Ob"edinenii v 1927 g.,", undated (Box-folder 27: 17-18)
        Includes originals and typescript copies of correspondence, 1926.
    - "Doklad po obsledovaniiu tsentra Biiankur," typescript, 1926 (Box-folder 27: 19)
    - List of newspapers used by editorial office, handwritten, undated (Box-folder 27: 20)
    - Readers' responses to
      - Borman, A. A., "Bol'shevistkaia merzost' na frantsuzskoi stsene,", 1927 April 3 (Box-folder 27: 21)
      - Struve, P. B., unidentified article, 1925 October 17 (Box-folder 27: 22)
    - Russian émigré organizations, miscellaneous material received by editorial office, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 28: 1-2)
      Includes invitations, announcements, and correspondence.
    - Correspondence
      - Unidentified, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 28: 3)
      - Abrosimov, Mikhail, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 4)
      - Agapaev, V., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 5)
      - Aide Aux Étudiants Russes, 1925 (Box-folder 28: 6)
      - Alekseev, D., undated (Box-folder 28: 7)
      - Alovskii, B. G., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 8)
      - An..., P., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 9)
      - Andreev, Vladimir, undated (Box-folder 28: 10)
      - Andreeva, N., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 11)
      - Andreevich, V., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 12)
      - Andreevskii, V., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 13)
      - Andro de Monzheron, N., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 14)
      - Anichkov, V. P., undated (Box-folder 28: 15)
      - Arakelian, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 16)
      - Arkhangel'skaia, Klavdiia, undated (Box-folder 28: 17)
      - Aristov, K. and Bylov, I., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 18)
      - Aronsberg, Emanuil M., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 19)
      - Arshaulov, V. P., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 20)
      - Ashkinazi, S., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 21)
      - Auerbach, W., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 22)
      - Azancheev, Aleksandr, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 28: 23)
      - Azarevich, Iu., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 24)
      - B. T., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 25)
      - Baikov, Boris L., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 28: 26)
      - Banque Marmorosch, Blank & Cie, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 27)
      - Baratynskii, Viacheslav, undated (Box-folder 28: 28)
      - Bardos, Stefan, 1925 (Box-folder 28: 29)
      - Baschmakoff, Alexander, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 30)
      - Baskin, K., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 31)
      - Bauer, K., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 32)
      - Belitts, Nikolai, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 33)
      - Belyi, Vladimir, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 34)
      - Bennigsen, Georgii, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 35)
      - Berblinger, Nicolas, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 36)
      - Berezhanskii, N., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 37)
      - Berg, L., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 28: 38)
      - Berkutov, Nikolai, 1925 (Box-folder 28: 39)
      - Berladnik-Pukovskii, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 40)
      - "Bessarabets,", undated (Box-folder 28: 41)
      - Bialotzky, Boris, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 42)
      - Bobkov, V. S., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 43)
      - Bodrukhin, V., undated (Box-folder 28: 44)
      - Bogdanova, M., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 45)
      - Borchtsch, Philippe, undated (Box-folder 28: 46)
      - Borman, A. A., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 47)
      - Brant, Kurt V., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 48)
      - Brasserie Bourgeoise a Pilsen, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 49)
      - Brevern, Anatolii, undated (Box-folder 28: 50)
      - Brianchaninov, A. N., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 51)
      - Britan, Iliia, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 52)
      - Bulatov, A., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 53)
      - Bunge, A., undated (Box-folder 28: 54)
      - Bychkovskaia, Anna, 1925 (Box-folder 28: 55)
      - Bykov, D., undated (Box-folder 28: 56)
      - Byval'kevich, P., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 57)
      - Chaiushchii podpischik, undated (Box-folder 28: 58)
      - Chelnokov, Mikhail, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 59)
      - Chernov, Nikolai, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 60)
      - "Chitatel',", 1926 (Box-folder 28: 61)
      - "Chitatel' Vozrozhdeniia,", 1925 (Box-folder 28: 62)
      - D., F., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 63)
      - Dalekoi, F., undated (Box-folder 28: 64)
      - Davatts, V., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 28: 65)
      - Deicha, A., 1924 (Box-folder 28: 66)
      - Dekhterev, Aleksandr P., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 67)
      - Dem'ianov, Aleksandr, 1926 (Box-folder 28: 68)
      - Denisov, G., undated (Box-folder 28: 69)
      - Deringer, A. V., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 28: 70)
      - Diterikhs von Diterikhsshtein, V. D., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 28: 71)
      - Dobrzhitskii, N., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 72)
      - Dolinskii, Semen, undated (Box-folder 28: 73)
      - Dolinskii, V., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 74)
      - Domracheev, M., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 75)
      - Donner, N., 1926 (Box-folder 28: 76)
      - Drabovich, V., undated (Box-folder 28: 77)
      - Drizen, N. V., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 78)
      - Drizo, M. Iu., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 28: 79)
      - Dzanti, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 80)
      - Dzhavakhov, Prince, undated (Box-folder 28: 81)
      - Elenev, Nikolai, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 28: 82)
      - Emmochka, 1927 (Box-folder 28: 83)
      - Epanchin, N., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 28: 84)
      - Epshtein, V., 1925 (Box-folder 28: 85)
      - Erdman, A., undated (Box-folder 28: 86)
      - Ermakov, N., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 87)
      - Evanguel, N., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 88)
      - Evgen'ev, S., 1927 (Box-folder 28: 89)
      - Ezerskii, N., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      - Fateev, D. I., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 2)
      - Felichkin, M., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 3)
      - Fietskii, M., undated (Box-folder 29: 4)
      - Filat'ev, Dmitrii, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      - Filat'ev, V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 6)
      - Finisov, P., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      - Fisher, Nikolai, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 8)
      - Fridlender, A., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 9)
      - Gailesh, K., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 10)
      - Gal'gern, I., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 11)
      - Galkin, Evgenii V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 12)
      - Gaug, Ekaterina, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 29: 13)
      - Gaush, Aleksandr, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 14)
      - Gavrilov, F., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 15)
      - Geimbiurger, A. I., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 16)
      - "Ge-ka,", undated (Box-folder 29: 17)
      - Gendrikova, E., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 18)
      - Georgievskii, P., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 19)
      - Gerasimov, V., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 20)
      - Gertron, Boris, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 21)
      - Gizhdeu, P. N., undated (Box-folder 29: 22)
      - Glazov, V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 23)
      - Glebov, I. A., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 29: 24)
      - Glindskaia, E., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 25)
      - Glovatskaia, O., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 26)
      - Gnoutoff, A., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 27)
      - Golitzin, A. V., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 28)
      - Gorbuntsov, Nikolai I., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 29)
      - Gordinskaia, A., undated (Box-folder 29: 30)
      - Gribunin, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 31)
      - Grigorash, V., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 32)
      - Grigor'ev, N. N., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 29: 33)
      - Grinevich, Dmitrii P., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 34)
      - Grodnitski, V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 35)
      - Grudinskii, Nikolai, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 36)
      - Griunman, F., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 37)
      - Grunberg, Eugene, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 38)
      - Gudim-Levkovivh, Pavel, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 39)
      - Guedalla, Herbert, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 40)
      - Gukasov, A. O., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 29: 41)
      - Gurevich, G. A., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 42)
      - Gust, Roman, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 43)
      - Hartong, Jean, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 44)
      - Iablonskii, Sergei V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 45)
      - Iakovlev, 1927 (Box-folder 29: 46)
      - Iakushev, Parfenii, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 47)
      - Ianitskii, Aleksandr, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 48)
      - Ianov, M., undated (Box-folder 29: 49)
      - Ianovskii, Vsevolod, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 50)
      - Idel'son, V. R., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 51)
      - Idson, Boris, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 52)
      - Il'in, V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 53)
      - Imprimerie de Navarre, 1928 (Box-folder 29: 54)
      - Indrikson, Fedor N., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 55)
      - Ishevskii, Dimitrii, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 56)
      - Iurchenko, Vsevolod P., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 57)
      - Iur'ev, P., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 58)
      - Ivanitskii-Ingilo, Rafail, 1927 (Box-folder 29: 59)
      - Ivanov, Aleksei, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 60)
      - Ivashkin, V., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 61)
      - Izraztsov, Konstantin, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 62)
      - Kadenko, Mikhail, 1927 (Box-folder 29: 63)
      - Kalitin, Petr P., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 29: 64)
      - Kalmykov-D'iachenko, F., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 65)
      - "Kamlo diu Rua, no ne Khuligana Prochitavshii,", 1927 (Box-folder 29: 66)
      - Karaszewicz, Jean, 1927 (Box-folder 29: 67)
      - Karkhaninov, Mikhail, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 68)
      - Karrik, V., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 69)
      - Kasatkin-Rostovskii, Fedor, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 70)
      - Katenev, Boris, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 29: 71)
      - Katenev, V., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 72)
      - Kazarin, G., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 73)
      - Kazum-Bek, D., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 74)
      - Khesin, Vladimir, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 75)
      - Khilkov, A. D., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 76)
      - Khodnev, D. M., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 77)
      - Khol'msen, I., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 78)
      - Kirianoff, E., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 79)
      - Kocherov, Ia., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 80)
      - Kocherva, V., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 81)
      - Kocherzhevskaia, Olga V., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 29: 82)
      - Kolachevskii, Vladimir M., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 83)
      - Kolokolov, N., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 84)
      - Koloshin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 85)
      - Kolosovskii, Viktor, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 86)
      - Kolpinskii, Diodor, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 29: 87)
      - Komarovskaia, O., 1926 (Box-folder 29: 88)
      - Kondratskaia, Iuliia, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 89)
      - Kopylov, Mikhail, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 90)
      - Korenev, A., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 91)
      - Korolevich, Petr M., 1927 (Box-folder 29: 92)
      - Koshelev, Gavriil, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 93)
      - Kotoman, A., undated (Box-folder 29: 94)
      - Koval'chuk, Vasilii S., undated (Box-folder 29: 95)
      - Kovalevskii, P. E., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 96)
      - Kozhevnikova, Olga, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 97)
      - Kozintseva, Vera, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 98)
      - Krasovskii, 1926 (Box-folder 29: 99)
      - Krishevskii, N., 1925 (Box-folder 29: 100)
      - Kriukov, Aleksei, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 29: 101)
      - Krivoshein, K. G., undated (Box-folder 29: 102)
      - Krotkevich, Viacheslav, 1925 (Box-folder 29: 103)
      - Krupenskii, Aleksandr N., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - Krylov, Dimitrii D., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 2)
      - Kryzhanovskii, Grigorii, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 3)
      - Ksiunin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 4)
      - Ksiunin, Sergei M., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 5)
      - Ktitarev, Iakov, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 6)
      - Kudriashin, Pavel, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 7)
      - Kudritskii, Dmitrii, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 8)
      - Kukol', P., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 9)
      - Kulum-Bek, Nikolai, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 10)
      - Kurochka, Ivan, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 11)
      - Kursinskii, A., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 12)
      - Ladnov, Evgenii, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 13)
      - Lena Goldfields Limited, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 14)
      - Leontovich, Evgenii, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 30: 15)
      - Levitskii, V. M., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 30: 16)
      - Likhachevskii, Antonii, undated (Box-folder 30: 17)
      - Litvinnik, Nikolai, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 18)
      - Liubimov, Leon, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 19)
      - Liubishchev, Dimitrii, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 20)
      - Lopatina, E. M., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 21)
      - Luchov, N., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 30: 22)
      - Lugovin, N., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 23)
      - Lukash, Ivan S., undated (Box-folder 30: 24)
      - L'vov, L. I., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 25)
      - Maidachevskii, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 26)
      - Makhine, B., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 27)
      - Maksheev, N. A., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 28)
      - Malama, V., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 29)
      - Mamontov, V., undated (Box-folder 30: 30)
      - Markevich, Sergei, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 31)
      - Markov, Anatolii, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 32)
      - Masianoff, Leon, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 33)
      - Maslov, E., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 34)
      - Medvedeva, Evgeniia, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 35)
      - "Mestnyi bezhenets,", 1926 (Box-folder 30: 36)
      - Mikhailov, M., undated (Box-folder 30: 37)
      - Mikhailov (Zubkov), V., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 38)
      - Milich, Elena, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 39)
      - Milikin, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 40)
      - Mineev, P., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 41)
      - Miroglio, A., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 42)
      - Miroshkin, E. S., undated (Box-folder 30: 43)
      - Misso, Petr, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 44)
      - Moguchii, E. V., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 45)
      - Mordukhovich, A., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 46)
      - Morozov, V., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 47)
      - Musorin, A., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 48)
      - Mustafin, V., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 49)
      - N., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 50)
      - Nakonechnaia, N., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 51)
      - Navratil', M., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 52)
      - Neander, Boris N., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 53)
      - Neiman, A., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 54)
      - Nemirovskii, A., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 55)
      - Niewiadomsky, Elisabeth, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 56)
      - Newiadomsky, N., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 57)
      - Nigolev, V., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 58)
      - Nikolaev, K., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 59)
      - Nikol'skii, B. A., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 30: 60)
      - Nikonov, Arsenii, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 61)
      - Nikonov, S., 1924 (Box-folder 30: 62)
      - Novitskii, N., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 63)
      - Obolenskii, N. L., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 30: 64)
      - Ochkin, N. G., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 65)
      - Ogurtsov, Leonid L., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 66)
      - Okhotin, Fedor T., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 67)
      - Ol'denburg, S. S., 1928 (Box-folder 30: 68)
      - Orekhoff, Basile B., undated (Box-folder 30: 69)
      - Orinitchev, Jean P., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 70)
      - Orlitskii, Nikolai L., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 71)
      - Orzhekhovskii, V., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 72)
      - Osipov, Ivan, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 73)
      - Osipov, Pavel, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 74)
      - Ostaf'ev, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 30: 75)
      - Ostrikov, Andrei I., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 76)
      - Ostroumov, S., undated (Box-folder 30: 77)
      - Ovchinnikov, Gavriil, 1927 (Box-folder 30: 78)
      - P. A., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 79)
      - Palei, Kniaginia, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 80)
      - Paleolog, Sergei, 1920, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 81)
      - Panas, I. O., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 82)
      - Parfenov, N., undated (Box-folder 30: 83)
      - Pashich, Nikola, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 84)
      - Pasmanik, D. S., undated (Box-folder 30: 85)
      - Pavlova, Elena Nikolaevna, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 86)
      - Pavlovskii, Sergei, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 87)
      - Perekrestov, Z., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 88)
      - Pervenko, E., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 89)
      - Petrov, S., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 90)
      - Petrov, V., 1927 (Box-folder 30: 91)
      - Pigarev, Aleksei, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 92)
      - Pinus, Sergei, 1925 (Box-folder 30: 93)
      - Plaksin, Boris N., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 94)
      - Pletnev, Aleksei, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 95)
      - Pletnev, Dimitrii A., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 96)
      - Podtiagin, B., undated (Box-folder 30: 97)
      - Pokhval, A., 1926 (Box-folder 30: 98)
      - Poklevskii-Kozell, S., 1925 (Box-folder 30: 99)
      - Pokrovskaia, Lidiia, 1926 (Box-folder 30: 100)
      - Pokrovskii, A., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      - Polezhaeva, N. M., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 2)
      - Polianskii, V. V., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 3)
      - Polinovskii, M., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 4)
      - Polovtsev, K., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 5)
      - Polunin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 6)
      - Ponafidine, E., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 7)
      - Popov, Aleksandr, V., undated (Box-folder 31: 8)
      - Popov, Ioann, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 9)
      - Porokhovshchikov, P., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 10)
      - "Postoiannyi chitatel' Vozrozhdeniia,", 1927 (Box-folder 31: 11)
      - Pozhidaev, P., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 12)
      - Pronin, G., undated (Box-folder 31: 13)
      - Pshemakho-Kotsev, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 14)
      - Puchkovskii, V., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 15)
      - R. Prefettura della Spezia, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 16)
      - Raevskii, N., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 17)
      - Rezanov, A., undated (Box-folder 31: 18)
      - Riasnianskii, S., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 19)
      - Rodionov, undated (Box-folder 31: 20)
      - Romanova, Olga, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 21)
      - Rozen-Meier, Elena, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 22)
      - Rozhdenstvenskii, N., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 23)
      - Rozin, Andrei, 1925 (Box-folder 31: 24)
      - Rubanov, G., undated (Box-folder 31: 25)
      - Rudin, Andrei, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 26)
      - Russ-Union, 1925 (Box-folder 31: 27)
      - "Russkaia,", 1927 (Box-folder 31: 28)
      - "Russkaia emigrantka,", 1927 (Box-folder 31: 29)
      - "Russkaia Matitsa,", 1926 (Box-folder 31: 30)
      - "Russkaia zhenshchina,", 1925 (Box-folder 31: 31)
      - "Russkii,", 1927 (Box-folder 31: 32)
      - Russkoe Slovo (Harbin), 1927 (Box-folder 31: 33)
      - Rybakoff, Nikolai, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 34)
      - S. A., undated (Box-folder 31: 35)
      - S. B., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 36)
      - Sablin, E., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 37)
      - Sagaidak, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 38)
      - Samsonov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 39)
      - Samsonova, V. M., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 40)
      - Sarafanov, N., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 41)
      - Savchenko, A., undated (Box-folder 31: 42)
      - Savin, V., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 43)
      - Sazonov, A., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 44)
      - Semenovskii, A. D., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 45)
      - Semykin, Ia. M., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 46)
      - Serebriakov, V., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 47)
      - Serge, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 48)
      - Sergeev, Khristofor N., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 49)
      - Sh. K., undated (Box-folder 31: 50)
      - Shakhovskoi, A., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 51)
      - Shat'ko (Voronina), Vera M., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 52)
      - Shchepinskii, Vladimir A., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 53)
      - Shchirovskii, S., undated (Box-folder 31: 54)
      - Shevliakov, Sergei, undated (Box-folder 31: 55)
      - Shmagailov, G., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 56)
      - Shmidt, N., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 57)
      - Shopin, Pavel, undated (Box-folder 31: 58)
      - Shtorkh, A., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 59)
      - Shtromberg, G., undated (Box-folder 31: 60)
      - Shustov, P., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 61)
      - Sidorov, Dimitrii, undated (Box-folder 31: 62)
      - Sizov, Fedor, 1925 (Box-folder 31: 63)
      - Skarskii, A., undated (Box-folder 31: 64)
      - Skoblin, N. V., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 65)
      - Skovronski, Stjepan, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 66)
      - Skvortsov, Vasilii, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 67)
      - Sladetskii, Arsenii, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 68)
      - Sliozberg, G., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 69)
      - Slutskii, Mikhail, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 70)
      - Smirnova, A., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 71)
      - Smuglov, Col., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 72)
      - Sobesskii, E., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 73)
      - Sokolov, B. N., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 74)
      - Sosnowski, P., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 75)
      - Spasskii, Aleksei, 1927 (Box-folder 31: 76)
      - "Staryi Drozdovets,", 1925 (Box-folder 31: 77)
      - Stivens, N. A., 1925 (Box-folder 31: 78)
      - Stroev, V., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 79)
      - Stroganoff, N., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 80)
      - Struk, Ataman, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 81)
      - Struve, Konstantin P., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 31: 82)
      - Stupenkov, A., undated (Box-folder 31: 83)
      - Svechina-Kishenskaia, V., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 31: 84)
      - Svetlov, V., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 85)
      - Sychov, Konstantin I., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 86)
      - T. A., 1927 (Box-folder 31: 87)
      - Taube (Anichkova), S., undated (Box-folder 31: 88)
      - Tatarinov, V. V., undated (Box-folder 31: 89)
      - T-v, F. S., undated (Box-folder 31: 90)
      - Teniere, Lucien, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 91)
      - Tereshchenko, Sergei, 1926 (Box-folder 31: 92)
      - Tereshkevich, N. F., 1926 (Box-folder 31: 93)
      - Terletskii, Nikolai, undated (Box-folder 31: 94)